《オビト : 俺が…。
Are you saying...
この俺が
後悔しているというのか？》
that I...
have regrets?
(ナルト)お前は 俺に→
You told me, "I'm no one...
I don't want to be anyone..."
誰でもない 誰でもいたくないって
言ったよな。
でも本当は 俺と一緒で
火影になりたかったんだな。
But the truth is...
You wanted to become
the Hokage, just like me.
面して自分隠したってダメだ。
You can't hide behind a mask.
アンタは カカシ先生の友達で
父ちゃんの部下で→
You were Kakashi Sensei's friend...
my dad's subordinate...
an Uchiha like Sasuke...
サスケと同じ うちはで→
俺と同じ夢持つ先輩で
木ノ葉の忍だった。
and a shinobi of the Hidden Leaf
who had the same dream as me!
俺と同じ夢持ってたアンタが
火影とは真逆になっちまった。
You used to have
the same dream as me.
But now you've become
the exact opposite of a Hokage!
俺と そっくりだったからこそ
お前が…。
It's because you're just
like me that...
いや だったからこそ→
No, it's because of that...
俺は この世界に絶望するお前を
見てみたかった。
That's why I wanted to see you
despairing about this world.
いや もう一度
実感したかったんだ。
Or... I suppose I wanted
to feel again for myself,
俺自身の進むべき道が
間違っていないことを。
that the path that I have chosen
for myself is not a mistake.
行き先も はっきりせず→
There's no need to voluntarily tread
a steep and rugged path,
わざわざ険しい道だと
わかっていて歩くことはない。
not knowing what's ahead.
仲間の死体をまたぐだけだ。
You'll have to step over
the corpses of your comrades.
はっきりした行き先があり
近道があるなら→
Anyone would choose a shortcut
with a fixed outcome.
誰でも そちらを選ぶ。
そう… 火影の目指すべき行き先は
世界の平和だ。
Yes... The goal a Hokage should
seek is world peace.
何 言ってんだ お前。
What are you saying?
俺が知りてぇのは
楽な道のりじゃねえ。
What I want to know about
isn't a shortcut...
険しい道の歩き方だ！
but how to navigate
the steep and rugged path!
一方が険しい道だって
最初に誰が教えてくれんだよ？
Who can tell in the beginning
which one is the dangerous one?
結局 誰かが歩かなきゃ
それもわかんねえだろうが。
You never know
unless you start walking.
火影ってのは 痛ぇの我慢して→
The Hokage is someone
who endures the pain
みんなの前を歩いてるヤツのことだ。
and takes the lead
in front of everyone.
だから仲間の死体を
またぐようなことは決してねえ！
So a Hokage never walks over
his comrades' corpses.
火影になるヤツに近道はねえし
なったヤツに逃げ道はねえんだよ！
There are no shortcuts for
the one who becomes the Hokage...
There's no running away
for the one who becomes the Hokage!
そうだろ!?
Isn't that right?
((ちょっと ヘマしちまった。
目に砂が入っちまって。
I messed up...
I got some dust in my eyes and...
(あっ 痛い！))
Oww!
リンって人が生きてたら
きっと こう言っただろうな。
I bet this Rin person would
say this if she were still alive...
強がって自分を隠すな って。
ちゃんと見てんだから ってよ。
"Don't act tough and
hide your wounds."
"I'm always watching."
((リン : あなたを救うことは
世界を救うのと同じなんでしょ。
You told me saving you
was the same as
saving the world, remember?
私が見張ってるってことは→
Since I'm keeping an eye on you,
もう何にも隠し事はできないよ。
you can't hide anything
from me anymore.
うん うん！
Okay! Okay!
頑張れ オビト！
Go for it, Obito!
火影になって かっこよく
世界を救うとこ見せてね！
Become Hokage and show me
how you'll save the world.
(それも約束だよ！))
That's another promise!
リンは… リンは俺にとっての
唯一の光明だった。
Rin...
Rin was my only light and hope.
リンを失って後
俺の見る世界は変わってしまった。
After I lost Rin...
the world as I saw it, changed.
真っ暗な地獄だ。
It became a pitch-black hell.
この世界に希望はない。
There's no hope in this world.
マダラになり代わって
世界を歩いたが→
I took Madara's identity
and walked the world.
更に それを確信するだけだった。
But all it did was confirm my belief.
この写輪眼をもってしても
結局は何も見えなかった。
Even with my Sharingan,
I couldn't see anything...
何もなかった。
There was nothing to see.
(カカシ)お前だって
見ようとすれば 見えたはずだ。
I'm sure you could've seen it too,
if you'd tried.
俺とお前は
同じ眼を持ってんだからな。
After all, you and I have
the same eyes.
信じる仲間が集まれば→
If comrades that you trust,
gather around you...
希望も形となって
見えてくるかもしれない。
hope can take physical form
and become visible.
俺は そう思うんだよ… オビト。
That's what I believe...
Obito.
ナルトの道か…。
Naruto's path, huh...
Ready, set, go, we step over the goal line
isse nou se de fumikomu gourain
Still, we don't know anything at all
bokura wa nanimo nanimo mada shiranu
We look back as we pass the line, and it's already gone
issen koete furikaeruto mou nai
Still, we don't know anything at all
bokura wa nanimo nanimo mada shiranu
Fiercely, fiercely we move on
udatte udatte udatteku
Drenched in glistening sweat
kirameku ase ga koboreru no sa
There probably were a lot of things we didn't remember
oboetenai koto mo takusan atta darou
Everyone was just a silhouette
daremo kare mo shiruetto
Let's become adults,
daiji ni shitai mono motte otona ni naru nda
holding on to things we want to cherish
And let's keep on protecting them at all times
donna toki mo hanasazu ni mamori tsudzukeyou
Then someday...
soshitara itsu no hi ni ka
We'll be able to laugh at it all
nanimo kamo o waraerusa
Like the light and nimble dancing
hirari to hirari to matteru
Of leaves taking flight
konoha ga tonde yuku
Madara Uchiha Arises
(柱間)仙法 明神門！
Sage Art: Gracious Deity Gates!
《ナルトの術では倒せなかったが→
Naruto's jutsu didn't bring him down,
これで ヤツの動きを
完全に封じることができた。
but with this,
he won't be able to move at all!
あとは 封印の忍を待つのみぞ》
All that's left is to wait for
the Sealing Shinobi.
ハァッ ハァッ ハァッ…。
(ミナト)尾獣を抜かれたということは
オビトは…。
Having the Tailed Beasts
extracted from him
means that Obito's...
(九喇嘛)十尾の人柱力は
他の人柱力と違う。
The Ten Tails' Jinchuriki aren't
like all the others.
尾獣を抜いても死にはせん。
They won't die if
the Tailed Beast is extracted.
十尾の殻…。
It's because the Ten Tails' husk,
the Gedo Statue remains.
つまり 外道魔像が残るからな。
ありゃ相当の生命力だ。
It contains a lot of life force.
本当かい？
なぜ そんなことがわかる？
Is that true?
How do you know?
おいおい なら誰が十尾のチャクラを→
Hey, now.
Who do you think scattered us
all across the world
９つに分散したあと→
各地へ散らしたりできる？
after splitting Ten Tails' Chakra
into nine pieces?
六道仙人…。
The Sage of Six Paths...
ただし９体も一度に
力を抜かれちゃ→
But with nine bodies extracted out
of him all at once,
死んだみてぇに弱りきって→
he'll be so weak it will
be like he's dead.
数か月は動けもしねえ。
He won't be able to move
for a few months.
かつてのじじいも そうだった。
Just as it was for
the old man back then.
そういうことか。
So that's how it goes.
カカシ 俺の中の九尾が
教えてくれたんだが…。
Kakashi...
the Tailed Beast inside me
just explained to me...
((オビト : そう 今のお前じゃ
リンには見向きもされねえよ。
That's right...
Rin won't even turn
to look at the current you.
(リンが見守りたかったのは
うちはオビトだ))
The one Rin wanted to watch over
is Obito Uchiha.
(ミナト)だから 心配しなくていいよ。
So you don't have to worry.
じゃあ 命には…。
Then... his life is...
今までの行為に対して
きっちりと報いてもらおう→
I was hoping he would atone
for all his past deeds, but...
と思っていたが…。
動けないなら しかたない。
It can't be helped if you can't move.
お前は そこで じっとしていろ。
Just stay put.
先生 オビトを
見張っていてください。
Sensei, please keep an eye
on Obito.
わかった。
All right.
(ミナト)何をしようとしている？
What are you trying to do?
かつて…
俺が利用しようとした男が…。
The same thing the man
I once tried to use...
俺を裏切った手段だ…。
did to betray me.
まさか…。
No way...
自分も同じことをするとは→
I never imagined I'd end up
doing the same thing...
思いもよらなかったがな…。
外道 輪廻天生の術だ。
It's the Gedo...
Art of Rinne Rebirth.
その術は 代わりにお前が…。
But that jutsu will result in your...!
《生を引きかえにする
術のようだね》
It seems to be a jutsu
that trades life for life.
長門が かつて→
I feel like I finally understand
why Nagato...
なぜ 俺を裏切ったのか→
今なら わかる気もする。
betrayed me back then.
数珠繋ぎの…。
A string of hearts linked together
like prayer beads...
重なった人の思い。
それも強い力になるんだな。
That can be a strong power
as well, huh...
長門も ナルトも自来也の弟子だった。
Nagato and Naruto were
both Jiraiya's students.
俺は… 自来也という人間に
負けたともいえる。
So you could say
Jiraiya defeated me.
先生… あなたの師であり→
Sensei...
He was also your master,
あなたを火影として育てた人。
the one who groomed you
to become the Hokage...
そして 俺は… あなたの弟子。
And I... was your student.
火影を諦め→
A shinobi who gave up
on becoming Hokage...
繋いだ思いを… 切った忍。
and cut all his ties.
向こうで リンに…。
I won't have much to say
to Rin on the other side.
合わせる顔が… ないか。
本当に それでいいのか？
Are you sure about this?
生きて償うことだって
できるんだぞ。
You could live and atone
for your sins...
いや そんな 生易しい…。
No... That's the easy way out.
(ゼツ)今度は 俺も協力してやる。
I'll help you out this time!
(マダラ)交代だ。
Time to switch places!
今度は こちらの攻める番だ。
It's now my turn to attack!
強がるな。 もう戦争は終わりだ。
Stop acting tough!
This war is over!
サイ！
(サイ)わかってる。
– Sai!
– I know!
封印術 虎視眈弾！
Sealing Jutsu!
Crouched Tiger Bullet!
ナルト…。
Naruto...
お前には感謝している。
I'm grateful to you.
オビトから
尾獣どもまで抜いてくれた。
You even extracted
the Tailed Beasts from Obito...
ヤツを弱らせる手間が省けた。
Saving me the trouble
of weakening him.
(ゼツ)悪いな オビト。
Sorry, Obito...
俺は このために
いたようなものなんだよ。
This is the reason
why I was stuck onto you.
黒ゼツ… ぐっ！
Black Zetsu!
W-What the—?!
よし もう少し！
Okay! Just a little bit longer!
(２人)輪廻天生の術！
– Art of Rinne Rebirth!
やっと まともに戦える。
Finally, I can fight for real!
グハッ！ ハァ ハァ…。
やはり この体でなければ。
This is the form,
the body I needed!
It's not a battle without raging blood...
and a pounding heart!
血湧き 肉躍ってこその戦いだ！
Ancient relics...
(サスケ)
旧時代の遺物が しゃしゃるな！
should just butt out!
A brat who doesn't even
come close to my level.
俺に届きもせん 砂利ごときが。
それは こちらのセリフだ。
You stole my line.
《なぜ目を閉じた？》
Why did he close his eyes?
Sasuke!
サスケ！
It's pointless to just
throw attacks at him.
コイツにただ忍術をぶつけても
意味ねえってばよ！
コイツは 忍術を吸収するんだ！
This guy can absorb ninjutsu!
相反する２つは作用し合い
森羅万象を得る。
It is these two polar opposites
operating together
that give rise to all things
in this universe...
柱間 かつて
うちはの石碑の前で→
Hashirama, do you remember me
telling you this long ago
in front of the Uchiha Stone Tablet?
お前に語ったのを覚えているか？
相反する２つの力が
協力することで→
That the inscription
on the stone says,
when two opposite sides cooperate,
you have true happiness.
本当の幸せがあると
記されている石碑だと。
だが 別のとらえ方も
できると言ったな。
But I also told you it could
be interpreted differently.
あれは…。
That's...
The one who obtains
both Uchiha and Senju powers
うちはと千手
両方の力を手にした者が→
can attain true happiness.
本当の幸せを手にする。
そういうとらえ方も
できやしないか？
Don't you think it could be read
that way as well?
柱間よ…。
Hashirama?
里を離れて なおも
いろいろと画策していたようだな。
It seems you've been doing
a lot of plotting
since you left the village.
No... Actually, this is something
いや これは部下の仲間が
偶然 仕組んだものだ。
my subordinate's comrade came up
with by coincidence.
俺と同じようなことを
考えた輩がいたらしい。
Seems there was a fellow
who thought a lot like me.
だが 再び生を受けたことは
計画どおりのものだ！
However...
Me coming back to life
was exactly as planned!
《クソ… 動けん！》
Damn it... I can't move!
ぐあっ！ うぅ…。
順番が逆になったが まあいい。
Though things did happen
out of order.
Oh well.
So this is Sage Art Chakra...
これが 仙術チャクラか…。
Is that all there is to it?
なんだ この程度の力か。
簡単に扱えそうだな。
Seems like this will
be easy to control.
生身の今こそ こちらのチャンスだ。
This is the perfect chance now
that you're flesh and blood.
This time I'll kill you for good,
これで確実に殺して
あの世に送り返すことができる。
and send you back
to the afterlife!
穢土転生のままがよかったと…。
Regret that you're still not
a reanimation...
悔やみながら逝け！
as you go to your death!
I can feel it...
感じるぞ その万華鏡は… 直巴。
Your Mangekyo are Choku Tomoe,
a straight pattern.
どうりで いい動きをする。
No wonder you have fine moves.
俺の輪廻眼が
帰ってくるまでの間→
It might be a good idea
to take your eyes
until I get my Rinnegan back.
お前の眼をいただくのも
いいかもしれんな。
オビト これでお前も用済みだ。
Obito... Your usefulness is over.
ハァ ハァ…。
何をした!?
What did you do?
マダラが… 生き返ってしまった。
Madara...
has come back to life!
You performed the Rinne Rebirth,
so you will die.
輪廻天生をしたお前は死ぬ。
This is the last step.
さて 最後の仕事だ
左眼は返してもらう。
I'm taking back that left eye.
俺が取りついている間→
He'll last a little while longer
while I'm attached to him.
少しは長持ちするだろう
コイツもな。
キミは何者だい？ 人ではないね。
Just what are you?
You're not human.
俺は マダラの意志そのものだ。
I am Madara's will incarnate.
I will eliminate anyone
who gets in Madara's way.
マダラの邪魔をするものは
排除する。
Black Zetsu.
黒ゼツ… 捕らえられたと
聞いていたが。
I thought you'd been captured...
このオビトもそうだが お前たちは
マダラの計画を甘く見すぎだ。
All of you, including Obito, greatly
underestimated Madara's plan.
そして 俺のこともな。
You underestimated me as well.
《こ これでは動けない。
I-I can't move now...
I can't believe he's able
to transform his blade so much
一瞬で刀の形状を
ここまで変化させるとは…》
in such an instant!
((ならちょうどよい。
お前は オビトのところへ行き→
Then that's perfect.
You'll go to Obito and
bide your time until
I give you the order.
命令があるまで時を待て。
こちらは
もう少し遊んでから向かう。
I'm going to play a little here,
then head over.
今の影どもの力も
知りたいところだ。
I just want to gauge
the present Kage's strength.
(わかった))
I got it.
マダラの策に
裏目に行動しおった役立たずだ。
He's a useless traitor
who went against Madara's plan.
オビトが死ぬまでの間
この体を使ってお前らと戦う。
Until Obito dies,
I'll use his body to fight you.
最後くらいは
役に立ってもらわねばな。
I've got to get some use
out of him,
at least at the end.
だが 殺すには惜しい眼だ。
But killing you would be such
a waste with an eye like that.
How about it?
どうだ 同じ
うちはの生き残りとして→
You're a survivor of
the Uchiha like me.
俺と組む気はないか？
Want to join forces?
勘違いするな。
お前は死んだ人間だ。
Make no mistake.
You're a dead man.
まぁいい。 どのみち
お前に残された時間は少ないぞ。
Fine then...
In any case,
you don't have much time left.
《火遁 灰塵隠れの術！》
Fire Style...
Hiding in Ash Jutsu!
《マダラは
かつての力を取り戻している。
Madara is regaining his past strength.
まずい ヤツが次に狙うのは…》
Not good. His next target is...
(みんな)うわ～っ！
I'll be taking you all next...
さぁ 次は お前らをいただくぞ。
ちくしょうども。
you filthy beasts!
kimi ni makechai sou na kurai
Almost to the point of losing to you
kimi ni nayamasare sou da
Feeling like you might torment me
kimi ni kikoecha dame dame dame da
Not wanting you to hear me no, no, no
kimi ni nagasare sou na kurai
Swept away by you
kimi ni shiteyarare sou da
Taken in by you
kimi o omoccha dame dame dame da
I shouldn't love you no, no, no
sugu wasurechatte dame da
It's not good that I'm so forgetful
uzukumattecha dame da
It's not good that I'm cowering
kizutsuitatte ana aitatte
Even if I'm wounded and pierced
massugu tatteirareruyou ni naritai
I want to be able to stand up straight
kimi ni makechai sou na kurai
Almost to the point of losing to you
kimi ni nayamasare sou da
Feeling like you might torment me
kimi ni kikoecha dame dame dame da
Not wanting you to hear me no, no, no
kimi ni nagasare sou na kurai
Swept away by you
kimi ni shiteyarare sou da
Taken in by you
kimi o omoccha dame dame dame da
I shouldn't love you no, no, no
The taste of this blood,
this pain...
This is my body!
I can finally experience
and feel this fight.
＜『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！ にっぽんの歌』。
He's bleeding and wounded.
今夜は 豪華な特別企画＞
In other words, he's not
a reanimation anymore.
How did he come back to life?
＜北島三郎さんをはじめ→
No way...
舟木一夫さん
ジャッキー吉川とブルー・コメッツなど→
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"The Hidden Heart"
No way... with Obito?
＜ まずは こちらの曲から
まいりましょう＞